<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Weeklies on 0xab.de</title><link>/weekly/</link><description>Recent content in Weeklies on 0xab.de</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/weekly/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Week 20, 2020</title><link>/weekly/2020/05/17/week-20-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/weekly/2020/05/17/week-20-2020/</guid><description>删了一些无意义的周报，大量的空白意味着一周没有做任何有意义的事，也许这会让我感到一些焦虑。
毕业论文写了5,000字左右，要求要达到15,000字。除此之外，还要求翻译一篇近五年的文献，想来近一个月没有翻译文章了，找时间把这篇Paxos vs Raft: Have we reached consensus on distributed consensus? 翻译一下。
听相声熬死同行那一段，似乎在行业内资历/年龄大便是绝对正确。同时联想起在一个表演节目上陈道明与同为评委的青年人对集体主义和个人主义的的不同观点，支持集体主义的陈道明获得了许多人支持，另一个青年人“无力反驳”。当然，抛开立场和观点来说，任何人在行业巨擎之前，哪怕是有独立的相反观点，谁又能与其客观争论下去呢？这样的辩论仿佛变得毫无意义。
到微博上看，支持LGBT的人仿佛正义的使者，对所有持相反观点的人恶语相向。“把无知当个性，把嘴臭当幽默。”凡事在政治正确的面前，一切理性和道德早已抛开。就事论事变成了满地打滚，自知理亏便撒娇打泼。“后浪们”在互联网上的素质展现的淋漓尽致，纵观整个中文互联网环境，凡是符合其利益，哪怕是违法行为也要被其包装称“英雄”。这一件事在之前在v2ex上就百度网盘事件上的讨论便能够看出。没等说两句话，小粉红、走资派、美分、公知的帽子便扣得飞起。
如果非要给我贴标签的话，大概会给我贴一个歪屁股的奋斗逼。但谁又能想到我有多讨厌华为就有多喜欢战狼呢？</description></item><item><title>Week 16, 2020</title><link>/weekly/2020/04/19/week-16-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/weekly/2020/04/19/week-16-2020/</guid><description>中文在计算机上的缺陷太大了，但是又不能完全舍弃中文输入法，所以我一直在寻找合适的输入法方式。非拉丁语系中，韩语的写法、读法及其相似：
곤란 골란 kollan 困難 而且重码率低。
日韩两国在输入汉语时会使用郑码，因此也作为国际通用码。台湾使用注音输入法，是因为在台湾注音符号得到很大推广，就像在大陆的拼音一样。此外还有仓颉、双拼的输入形式。
而常用的全拼输入法，重码率最高，输入字母数最多。但因为拼音在大陆的推广程度最高，使用人数最多（我爷爷还是后来自学的）。程序员群体有一部分选择了双拼的输入形式，但重码率达不到最低。我想要的是重码率最低，不需要选词，接近于英文输入的输入形式。但是郑码在平台兼容性上不如五笔，所以暂时选择五笔输入。多数字词不用选择直接上屏，爽！</description></item><item><title>Week 13, 2020</title><link>/weekly/2020/03/29/week-13-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/weekly/2020/03/29/week-13-2020/</guid><description>大概读完了 GFS 的论文。细节太多，加上读英文原文的需要的精力太大，所以用了很长时间。如果想要实现简单的估计要考虑的更多，不过估计会是给 HDFS 贡献一些代码。
leetcode 第二轮差不多做了130多道题，的的确确不太想做了，估计这几天就是尾声了。
翻以前的周报可能会发现这次改成了中文，因为词汇量匮乏太严重了。当然阅读没有问题，只是到写的时候难免想不到特别贴地气的表达方式。
放了一个多月的贴膜游戏干到星耀3了。除了毕设不想做，实在是没事情做，不过明天必须得开始了&amp;hellip;下周，也就是明天大概看看Hadoop MapReduce 源码，无论是工作内容还是6.824都与之强相关，bigtable 可能会放在 Raft 之后进行，不过 Raft 已经看过很多遍了，这次应该不会消耗很多时间。</description></item><item><title>Week 12, 2020</title><link>/weekly/2020/03/22/week-12-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/weekly/2020/03/22/week-12-2020/</guid><description>The winter vacation homework completed at Monday.
Google MapReduce paper have completed for weeks, the GFS and Bigtable were in the schedule. Excpet to the consensus algorithms, it seems that not too difficult. So next stage is to implement a simple MapReduce system.
It is a torment to wait for going to school. 快开学吧。</description></item><item><title>Week 11, 2020</title><link>/weekly/2020/03/15/week-11-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/weekly/2020/03/15/week-11-2020/</guid><description>Homework of winter vacation distributed by netease is approaching to the end.
netease-erver1 is written with Spring Boot, which I have used for 3 years. This time I wrote detailed mocking tests which never had before. To simplify the logic, I reduce the progress of the system. From design to completeing it, less than 4 days (I don&amp;rsquo;t want to write it till the deadline.) were used. Most of the time costed by writting test cases.</description></item><item><title>Week 10, 2020</title><link>/weekly/2020/03/08/week-10-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/weekly/2020/03/08/week-10-2020/</guid><description>I am in a dilemma at learning rust or golang, which I know a litte for the sake of labs. Matering in a specific language or, broading my skill stack is an equivalent puzzle. I have too little vigor to dig into much knowledge, like what Chuang Tzu said,
&amp;ldquo;吾生也有涯，而知也无涯。以有涯隨无涯，殆已；已而為知者，殆而已矣。為善无近名，為惡無近刑。緣督以為經，可以保身，可以全生，可以養親，可以盡年1。&amp;rdquo;
Though do not agree with part of the view of Chuang Tzu, I must admit no one can gain all knowledge in the world.</description></item><item><title>Week 9, 2020</title><link>/weekly/2020/03/01/week-9-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/weekly/2020/03/01/week-9-2020/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about pausing the daily algorithms but starting the weekly contest&amp;hellip;just thinking.
I sware it is my last time to shut down my process on android development, spending time on meaningful aspects is my future task.
It was my first practice on TDD and got a lot of improvement in programming skills. This can help me write robust code and prevent myself from waterfall-like midification. Later days from now, though dislike but must write some front-end code to complete my task distributed by my company.</description></item><item><title>Week 8, 2020</title><link>/weekly/2020/02/23/week-8-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/weekly/2020/02/23/week-8-2020/</guid><description>Approached to 100 solutions in this phase, I feel a bit bored with the leetcode problems. As what I want to handle with is the project something like infrastructure, platform&amp;hellip;With the ending up the development of service for a Android application, a conclusion was drawed: I hate monotonous crud bussiness. It is always a good symbol to find ones ambiton like what the motto in the homepage goes:
Adhere to the technological belief, be pragmatic, self-motivated, take responsibility to the end and fulfill others.</description></item><item><title>Week 7, 2020</title><link>/weekly/2020/02/16/week-7-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/weekly/2020/02/16/week-7-2020/</guid><description>Till now 89 problems in leetcode were sloved in this phase, 7 in this week as usual.
MIT 6.824: Distributed Systems requires a precondition that reading through the Google MapReduce paper. I finished it and ready to start this course. The CMU 15-213 course was put on hold because I have some basic related and now former is an emphasis.
These days I wrote some bussiness code that makes me collapse.</description></item><item><title>Week 6, 2020</title><link>/weekly/2020/02/09/week-6-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/weekly/2020/02/09/week-6-2020/</guid><description>It is a milestone for me to build my site with English, which inspires me to improve my level at this language. Ever after now, I write articles in English, twitte in English and read original professional articles (what I have done, in fact).
This week, I
sloved 7 algorithm questions in leetcode, 81 questions totally this phase. translated 2 articles, one for distributed systems, one for experience of learning english.</description></item><item><title>Week 49, 2019</title><link>/weekly/2019/12/01/week-49-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/weekly/2019/12/01/week-49-2019/</guid><description>挑了一本上周下载的 Operating Systems: Three easy pieces 1. 来读，这次尝试不用翻译阅读，起初看地比较吃力，后来觉得越来越顺畅了。这本书从虚拟化、并发和持久化三个方面介绍，这种结构更容易把知识打穿，也是我选择这本书的原因。读了7个 chapter 也发现了几个问题，和群里的朋友们探讨了一下：
Q1: 获取系统时间(gettimeofday())是否会进行系统调用？ Switching Between Processes A Non-Cooperative Approach: The OS Takes Control
A timer device can be programmed to raise an interrupt every so many milliseconds; when the interrupt is raised, the currently running process is halted, and a pre-conﬁgured interrupt handler in the OS runs. At this point, the OS has regained control of the CPU, and thus can do what it pleases: stop the current process, and start a different one.</description></item><item><title>Week 48, 2019</title><link>/weekly/2019/11/24/week-48-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/weekly/2019/11/24/week-48-2019/</guid><description> 之前实习的时候写过一段时间的周报，最近觉得需要记录一下自己的生活和学习的过程，避免过地无所事事。所以在今天专门在博客上开了一个周报的 tab，这便是我个人的第一个周报，或者说是周记。
电脑终于到了，是19款13&amp;rdquo; 16+512的，新出的16&amp;rdquo;低配也是16+512套餐，看了看钱包只能安慰自己是为了便携度放弃了16&amp;rdquo;。
折腾了三年多，最后还是迁回 Hugo1 搭建博客，之前一直使用 Travis CI2 做 CD，但是很久没用遇到了 Travis 中 Hugo 下载失败的问题。联想 GitHub Actions 上线不久，调研了相关的静态博客方案后选择了 Hugo + GitHub Pages + GitHub Actions 的方案。参照 hugo-xmin3 主题加入代码高亮4和 disqus5 评论，修改了一些样式，最后完成了你现在所在的这个站点6。
完成了一家公司的二面，起初电话没有听清是哪家公司，后来询问业务才想起只有一家投递了这个部门。有两个多月没有面试过了，一些常见的面试题也忘得差不多。平时能展开滔滔不绝的问题也被面试官问：“你面试别的公司说话也这么简短吗”？其实这些问题根本算不上难，背一些面经也可以回答上来。对我来说合理的面试内容应该是深入挖掘底层基础，一些依靠背诵或阅读几篇文章就能达到同样效果的问题确实让人头疼。身边有相当一部分朋友后悔学习计算机相关专业，我深切地理解这种做着不感兴趣的事的无力感，同时也庆幸自己对计算机科学及行业的热爱。四年间接触过一些能力极强的朋友，不得让感慨：真正的大神还是兴趣驱动，而没有任何功利的想法。 图1，本科期间的一部分计算机相关书籍
在网上7下了不少的英文原版 pdf，起初是为了看 DDIA8 这本书，后来由于收集癖好将所有计算机方面的经典书籍都下了一遍放在 icloud 上。
胸口不舒服有一周了，周日去医院看了看，片子拍出来后大夫告知是熬夜导致的。以后不能熬夜了，待恢复几天后也要加强锻炼。
https://gohugo.io/ ↩ http://travis-ci.org/ ↩ https://github.com/yihui/hugo-xmin ↩ https://highlightjs.org ↩ https://disqus.com/ ↩ https://arjenzhou.github.io ↩ https://www.pdfdrive.com ↩ https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1449373321/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=dataintensive-20&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;creativeASIN=1449373321&amp;amp;linkId=7b365b768a6f6c8e5e397e48e30d435e ↩</description></item></channel></rss>